Ahmed Mohamed Reda

Front-End Developer

9 6 ()

GPA: 2.8 (70%)

(+20) 1145809984

□ asayed565565@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Mid-Leve front-end with 2 years of experience building websites and web applications using ReactJS and modern JavaScript tools/frameworks, seeking a challenging and rewarding position as a full-stack developer where I can apply my skills in programming to deliver high-quality solutions.

♀ Giza

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Commerce English section

2016-2020

Cairo University

Accounting department

Front End Developer (React.js)

October 2023 - February 2024

Route Academy

EXPERIENCE

Front-end Developer (intern.)

March 2024 - April 2024

Prodigy InfoTech

- Assisting in Front-end Development: Collaborating with the development team to create and modify web interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Documenting code changes, writing clear and concise comments, and maintaining code repositories for future reference.

Merchandise Developer & Help Desk

February 2021 - December 2023

ACTIV ABOU ALAA

- Merchandise Developer & control
 - Review & check the new merchandise and collect data
 - Adjustment prices of the merchandise on the program
 - Main member of the stocktaking committee
- Help Desk
 - Follow-up computers for employees
 - Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure
 - Install and configure software and hardware
 - Set up accounts and workstations

System Administration

February 2018 – June 2020

JFL ACTIV

- Installing and configuring software, hardware and networks
- Monitoring system performance and troubleshooting issues
- Ensuring security and efficiency of IT infrastructure
- Monitor performance and maintain systems according to requirements

PERSONAL ACHIEVEMENT

#louvreinnovations

Overview: site for interior decoration works for a company, displaying their bio &

projects

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

#Yummy

Overview: Discover new and interesting cooking recipes on this website!

The website offers a diverse range of recipes organized by region, ingredient, and meal type, making it easy to find exactly what you're looking for.

rype, making ir easy to tind exactly what you're looking

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, API, jQuery

#Egyptian party

Overview: a simple responsive website using jQuery

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

#Weather App

Overview: The Weather-Forecast JS app is a user-friendly web tool for checking real-time weather forecasts. Developed with, it uses a weather API to provide users with essential details like temperature, and wind speed. And geolocation API to access the user's location information with their permission.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, API

#Login APP

Overview: A simple App This system consists of:

- 1- Sign-up form for users to register with a unique email address, name, and password.
- 2- Sign-in form for logging in with email and password.
- 3- The home page displays the user's name upon successful sign-in.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Font Awesome

#Bookmarker

Overview: A user-friendly website URL bookmarker that easily saves and organizes your favorite websites.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Font Awesome, CRUD Logic

#Random Quotes

Overview: The JS application generates random quotes.

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript

#DANIAL

Overview: The portfolio site, is a fully responsive website featuring seven sections and a

user-friendly navbar

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

TRAINING - COURSES

Online Courses

- IT Help desk - Web Development (El-Zero) - Master Python (El-Zero)

Python Diploma [Flask-Django Frameworks]

September 2022 – December 2022

IT Sharks

SKILLS

Software Skills:

- Languages: Python - HTML – CSS - Java Script - SCSS - TypeScript

- **Libraries:** React.js – jQuery

Frameworks: Bootstrap

- **Tools:** GitHub - VS Code - Figma

Language skills:

- Arabic [Mother tongue] - English [Very Good]

Personal skills:

- Problem solving skills. - Team player

- Excellent Communication Skills - Research & Analysis

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

- Date of birth: 16th May 1998 - Military status: Exempted